Wyatt here. And on today's segment of Stable Coins in DeFi, I was joined by Dave Taylor,
founder of Etherviews. Etherviews issues non-US stable coins and stable bonds for currencies
and treasuries with a focus on Mexico, other Latin markets and beyond. I hope you enjoy this
episode and here is my conversation with Dave. Matt Walsh and Nick Carter are partners at Castle
Island Ventures. All of these expressed by them or the guests on this podcast are solely their
opinions and do not reflect the opinions of Castle Island Ventures. Guests and hosts may maintain
positions in the assets discussed in this podcast. You should not treat any opinion expressed
by anyone on this podcast as a specific inducement to make a particular investment or
follow a particular strategy, but only as an expression of their personal opinion.
This podcast is for informational purposes only.
Dave, founder of Etherviews, thank you for joining us on the podcast. Very excited to chat
today. I think you guys are doing some very interesting things. Would love to kick off
with a personal introduction from yourself if you don't mind so that we can get to know you a bit
better. Yeah, thanks for having me. I really appreciate it. Happy to be here. I do listen to
the podcast quite a bit and so it's going to be nice to drive my son to school in the mornings
and I listen to it and he's going to hear my voice in the next one. So it's going to be cool.
Awesome. My background is computer science. I've worked in security, like software engineering
security for quite some time. I started out just in my companies. We call them startups now, but
when I was a graduate in Arizona, you just call them companies. I ended up working at Boeing
for quite some time. I did PKI management and a lot of like the API design for securely signing
software there. Then I went to Apple. I did a lot of network security and a lot of design between
how to normalize or standardize how secure software is used at Apple. Felt an awesome need to continue
to punish myself and grow and so I decided to go to business school at that point. Having had
like 10 years as a computer scientist and I went to business school and I met a good friend of mine.
He started this company called SendGrid, which you probably heard of. They were bought by Twilio
when we're in business school together. He IPOed and said, hey, I want to start a startup studio.
The important part is it kind of got some startup chops or at least some familiarity with how hard
it is and how it works. We launched a few companies together. It was a great experience and one of
the companies we launched together is Neural Payments. Neural Payments is a huge, huge in-scope
payments company in the U.S. Competitor to like Zell. I think they're raising their Series B right
now. They've done pretty well in a competitive market, but what was interesting with that is
we brought on a CTO at the time, who is now my co-founder, AJ, who's also my brother, by the
way, and together we built the mechanism to send money outside of ESA's rails from one account to
the next. It was just this crazy feat of how difficult it was, how antiquated it was, how hard
it was, and it really became like astonishing to us how what we see is not what happens in our
purview or I would say the periphery of what we're focused on. You start to hear the blockchain
getting quicker and faster and it just became obvious to us that this was like the future,
even though I was pretty comfortable, we were working on some cool stuff.
We said, hey, I think the blockchain is the future, so let's get into it.
Up until this point of etherfuse, that was my history as an engineer who jumped into business
and started some startups and then went headfirst into probably, I would say, one of the more complex
things I've ever done in my life. And to be clear, you discovered crypto after you became a businessman
in business school. That wasn't during the engineering period.
I was always on the sidelines. I always said, oh, I should have bought Bitcoin. I was more into
being a software engineer and into cryptography, the old school one. After really feeling the pain
of payments, it was real when I started to think about it and go, holy crap, this is the future.
And a bit to the point of etherfuse, were you a Bitcoiner early on or were you interested in,
it sounds like you highlighted the cryptography piece and maybe what you could do with assets
more broadly? I really only focused on PKI, so I wasn't a Bitcoiner back then. In fact,
I thought about it, I think in 2013, my neighbor worked for Google, the story kills me.
And I went and I bought like a little Arduino or something, because everyone was mining on nothing
back then. I was like, oh, I'm going to figure out how to mine. And he stopped me, he said,
you're too late, it's already done. And so I just kind of gave up on the idea and I kind of
hate him now. That was not correct. But I think it was like 2013 or 2012. So I could have avoided
all this stress and just gone straight to owning Bitcoin. Yeah, probably the person who's had the
most adverse monetary effect on your life. Exactly. And he doesn't even know it. I haven't even told
him so. Speak a little bit more to etherfuse if you don't mind. You guys are broadly in the stable
coin space as opposed to the Bitcoin and other asset space. I can take off from where I left
off with my personal story into how we started etherfuse, and then that can kind of lead into
our mission. But we three years ago said, okay, everyone at the time was proposing that nothing
on chain was a security. Like they would probably, this isn't a security. And we just hypothesized,
well, what would the workload look like if we said it was a security? It did some research
in the US on how we could do it. And it just became overwhelmingly obvious, like we're going to get
nowhere in the US. And so our goal was, okay, let's tokenize the security, say it's a security,
how do we do that? And so we did a bunch of research on the world and said, where did the
incentives lie? Meaning what's the biggest nation where the economy and the demographics of that
nation are such that if we could bring in the tokenization of assets on chain,
that the government would benefit quite a bit from it and the nation would benefit from it.
And if we can find that, then we'll go there because we think if we engage with regulators
there that they'll be incentivized to say yes. So back then it was like, we looked at remittance
flows, cost of credit, financial access, what percentage of the population has access to finances
and the ability to move money. And so back then there were three big ones. It was India, China,
and Mexico. Just kind of thought for one second, would China let us come in and build a security
on chain and influence their monetary system and felt, no, that's not going to happen. I've actually
done a lot of work with India at Apple. And India is a great country, of course, but is also pretty
defensive to foreign products. And so we felt, okay, we're going to hit a roadblock here. Look
deeper and deeper in Mexico and just felt like, hey, we think we could make an impact here. So
three years ago we went to Mexico and we started to interface with, it's a funny story, we literally
just went there and were like, okay, where's the lawyer? Where's the bank? And learned how we could
interface with the SEC of Mexico, it's called the CNBV, inquired if there's a process for new
technology. And we found out there was a process. It's called the sandbox model. They have similar
ones around the world. I think it's based off the one in England. But you could engage the CNBV
and you could say, hey, we have this new technology, it's a net good for the country. And we propose
doing it. And we think this is a security and we think that you should regulate it and tell us how.
We worked with them for two years. And the irony is, they came back and told us, we don't think this
is a security after the first year. And so then we went back and said, actually, we're pretty sure
it's a security, which this is counter to what's happening in the world. Everyone else is like
proposing nothing's a security. So we re-engage with them three times. And the third time we
asked them to write publicly all the reasons why our protocol does not constitute a security. So
the final thing we got from them is a no action letter stating why things designed as they are
through our protocol do not constitute a security. And when was that? What year did you get the
new action letter? It was like a year and a half ago. No action letter a year and a half ago,
that was valuable. What we did is if you go to our app, it gives us a huge competitive advantage
in Mexico. And so what we did is we kind of like the FBI does, we blacked out anything that gives
a huge competitive advantage. And then we had a judge notarize it, making the statements that say,
I agree that this document says, either of you can do what they can do. We've used that to essentially
establish the relationships with big banks like BBVA and Actin Ver and Santander and all around
the world to integrate with the banking system there. So it's been hugely valuable for us. I
think even if you sold our company for parts, it's worth quite a bit. We're the only company in
Mexico with any sort of guidance on how to tokenize assets. And Mexico is quite a big economy.
So that's how we got started. That's the genesis of Etherfuses. Go out, do some work and get guidance
on how to tokenize assets. I love that you guys took the approach of what if everything is a security
and where can we go to produce the most value at a time when most people are taking the attitude of
what is the biggest market and let's somehow not be a security? Yeah, we looked at it as
I felt the blockchain was like the internet. So it's like, okay, I make a website from the U.S.
but people from Europe can go there. And so if I can comfortably be regulated somewhere
and I can connect to the blockchain, I have a connection to this global economy.
We looked at it as like this opportunity. So let's go where the likelihood.
I still think it's a contrarian move today, even though we've told people Mexico is really hard.
So we did get lucky in some capacity. It's not become like a standard. Like since then,
I'd say Debye's become a standard. The Caymans become a standard. Some U.S. treasury loopholes
have become a standard, but people still aren't going to Mexico. So it's kind of interesting.
Yeah, that was kind of our outlook, though, is where Warren Buffett's shown me the incentives.
So we really were like, where are the incentives that raise the probability that we'll have success?
To cap off the story, you were telling you guys receive a no action letter in Mexico
and what are the products that you guys then venture into that we would see today?
So now we have the ability to tokenize anything. And we actually have API access to the stock
exchange in Mexico. We're like, okay, what could we do? We could do anything. We tried a few things,
but we really kind of had a second order like thought, what do we do that we think we can win?
And so we looked around in history and the world and just felt like there's not really the supply
for, I would say, the most popular, most boring investments in the world. We see a lot of need
in history for government debt on chain. And we see a lot of demand for it. And we don't really see
that opportunity on the blockchain. And we don't also see entrepreneurs or people focused on it.
We see them focused on US Treasuries, but we don't see them focused on other things. So
we decided to take a sliver of our opportunity and potential. And we decided to become the company
that will provide the APIs and SDK or contract endpoint to tokenize the world's sovereign debt
on chain, to tokenize the shortest term treasuries with the largest amount of liquidity from each
country, and to make that available through interest-bearing stablecoins. And so that is
our mission statement. That's where we're focused. We did raise a series, a small seed round. And so
we said, let's do five assets to prove who we are, make some traction and move forward. So the five
assets we tokenized were US Treasuries, European Treasuries, British Treasuries, Brazilian Treasuries,
and Mexican Treasuries. And three of those five were the only company in the world who has the
ability to do those. Where early on did you see captive demand for those non-US Treasuries on
chain? I think more we saw gaps in what happens in Treadfy versus what's happening in the blockchain.
So I think if I took that lens, where is the demand in the blockchain? It's a good question,
but it assumes that the right people are already on the blockchain. I think a lot of the demands
right now are highly speculative protocols, infrastructure. That's what I'm seeing. But I
think 10 years from now, it's going to be a totally different ecosystem. So really, we thought what's
missing that historically has needed to be there before a nation grew in size. And it was bonds.
If you look back, what built Europe, it was bonds, the interface of the bond. It was less
demand and more of caten the hatting it. Where is it not? And then also the need. We saw last
mile needs everywhere. Everyone wants to send money via remittance wallet, but then you see them
and they just wrap like USDC and then nothing. There's this missing last mile that we felt we
could fulfill. Since we've issued and promoted and pushed them out, we've partnered with people to
enable places that are not in Mexico and Brazil to issue stable coins in those currencies using
us a collateral. And we've seen demand there. We've seen that grow there. If you look at DeFi,
you look at our MXNE, which is what we call sovereign coin. So it's a stable coin denominated
in foreign currency, which uses our assets as collateral. We see quite a bit of activity
trading and using those for payments. Yeah, I like the framing there. We pick up efficiencies
on chain being faster settlement. Anyone can have an account, but the thought experiment of
where do we not see systems exist, where we do in TradFi that create efficient systems.
And it just seems like an unsustainable reality that you have US dollars on chain and you're
going to have to go off chain to turn into any other sovereign currency when we live in a world
with how many sovereign currencies? I don't know the exact number. Well, there are 127 countries,
so something close to that number. We all talk about remittances, right? But
remittances doesn't work without an off ramp in the alternative country. I feel like the biggest
frustration with crypto or the blockchain today is the lack of understanding of where needs are
versus like, hey, how much TVL does this product have? That's what I'm going to focus on at the
moment. There's a lot of innovation that needs to happen still. We need to make space for that.
I guess that's kind of how I feel about it. In recent on chain asset terms, we've had Bitcoin
for a long time. We've had Ethereum and Solana and then Longertale for a long time. We've seen
the rapid rise of stablecoins now to some $230 billion market cap. Do you see the potential
rise of the MXN stablecoin and other stablecoins that you guys operate in as being commercially
driven and that people will want to own them for investment purposes? Or do you see it as more of
a workflow insert where the on ramp and off ramping from and to USD needs to become more
efficient? And because of that, it makes sense to have an MXN stablecoin. I think the first set of
demand is going to come from the fact that we are going to make on and off ramping from a local
nation near free, free or near free, depending on your use case, free for T plus one for sure.
I think that will drive so much demand and trust of being able to on and off ramp that directly
to a self custody wallet that we'll see those volumes grow quite a bit. I think people will
start to recognize that since they yield for these underlying assets are much higher than like,
you know, safer products, that our revenue opportunities are 10x those of normal stablecoins
that you'll start to see people pay attention. So I think that's the first order of effect.
The second is it's ironic, but everything is happening with tariffs is really good for us.
It's our idea. Because if you want to exchange, you know, your USDC or like our Mexican say taste
product, it is currently outperforming as a store of value US denominated products. And so there's
going to be chaos in my opinion for the next two years as we figure this out. If you wanted to move
safe assets on chain into a different product, we're the only company that currently enables
you to do that. So I think that there will be a lot of demand once people understand the potential.
We built the trust gap and they trust us. And just as an example, like we magnify US products too. So
if you go to I'm trying to think what's your blockchain of choice, I'll just pick Solana
as an example. If you go to Camino, you could like short a US Treasury and do something with it,
or you could invest in one that's there. But it's possible to buy say taste short it and then with
that by a US Treasury. And now I've have my US Treasury yields, but I also have any underperformance
of that emerging market. So I could boost yields up by five or 6% just by shorting something else
first. And this is a huge market in triad five currency forwarding currency options. And DeFi is
a better, more efficient place to do it. And so I think once we are effective as a company
communicating and people trust us, they see we have the volumes, we have the transparency and the
security for those investments, it'll explode. And retail of the individuals are completely
excluded from that. Like I can go to cash, but I can't go in my Chase account and say, okay,
I want to be in pesos for the next six months. It's impossible. Use a US person right now if you
wanted to buy like just Mexican Treasuries, you have to go through like an ETF through JPMorgan
Trace here. And they're returning like 6% yields. What are the fees on that? 3%. They're skimming
about 3%. You go to us, you get full minus our take. So it's like eight or 9%. So it's way better.
It's way more efficient to go through us. In addition to if you wanted to hedge a currency,
say you wanted to buy pesos, but you want to hedge it with the dollar, that's a complex
triad five product that's not really possible to do with like 300 bucks, but it's totally possible to
do on chain. And to your point about the inefficiency that we have, I think a lot of people, especially
users of crypto and even traditional financial venues in the US don't have an appreciation
of that globally. I've tried to learn myself about the proliferation of Binance peer-to-peer
and these peer-to-peer on-ramps that you have, which is such a stark contrast to you have such
efficient systems actually outside the US in what I would call traditional payments with things like
PIX in Brazil. Are those systems that you guys have integrated with any capacity that you've
utilized? And is there a reason that the product potentially functions better outside the US in
any capacity like that? Yeah. I mean, you hit the nail on the head. For some reason,
we have one of the worst payment systems in the world, probably because we just have a lot of
complexity, but in Mexico, there's SPAY. It's real-time, so settlement in seconds. PIX,
our goal for each asset is to enable on and off-ramping for free or near free, depending
on the scenario. So anytime there's a real-time payment system like PIX, we can do it for free.
If you just think about it, we own the asset in that country. We just have to sell it.
So if I can send funds to my brokerage immediately, I can also issue a token immediately.
If I can burn that and then issue a sell order immediately, I can sell it and send it to you
immediately. So Mexico is our first pilot for on and off-ramping that will officially be available
to the public next week. We are relatively certain that we'll be able to mint a token on-chain
denominated in peso for free and on-ramp fit for free, at least two plus one. And depending
if we can get the yield of the volume to match the cost of a microloan, it'll probably also be free
to be instant. But worst-case scenario, instant is five to seven BIPs. So it's a huge improvement
over what exists today. If you look at TradFi, it's like 7%. If you look at Efficient TradFi,
it's three. If you look at current state of stables, it's like 1%. 100 BIPs. So this is like
a 10x of the best thing out there. So we're really excited by it and we hope it leads to trust in our
asset and that our assets proliferate because of that. So PIX is next. We're almost set up there.
Officially, we'll go to PIX in July. I feel like we have an industry-wide innovators dilemma
in U.S. fintech and finance because the system is so entrenched and you have people are profiting. So
immensely off of the credit cards is off of the way our bank accounts function that
my view at least is especially in the context of stablecoins, it's going to be
a reverse adoption for us, which is you get it in these other countries with smaller economies
and then eventually we'll be the late adopters. I think so. I also think that the reason the U.S.
has done so well is historically it's proven to be a good place to start a company and a big economy.
And I think that still is. I think you've got to be a little crazy to do what we're doing,
go to a country and be like, how's it work here? Where's the bank? It did take a little insanity.
I'm happy we were crazy enough to do it. We've gotten all the roadblocks out of the way now for
us to just scale efficiently given the right tools and resources. I think it took a little bit of
insanity for us to do it. I talked to a prominent startup investor. I said what I was going to do,
he's like, don't do that. That's a crazy idea. That's how you know you have to go and do it,
right? A little bit of stubbornness. I was like, whatever, man.
For clarification, you guys are a U.S. company?
We're multinational. We have Etherfuse Inc. It's our cap table, essentially. And then our
subsidiaries are in these local countries. So the main one, Etherfuse MX, our regulatory umbrella
is through Etherfuse MX. So our operations and the issuance of our assets are all out of Mexico.
And then due to some investor feedback, we did set up some operations in Switzerland. So we
issue out of Mexico and then we tokenize under Swiss regulation. And I imagine without touching on
the secret sauce too much, the entity set up and the structuring here is a big part of the undertaking,
I would imagine. Compare Brazil and Mexico. Brazil is pretty sophisticated. It's kind of
straightforward how to set up a company. Mexico is super complicated. It's super slow and super
costly. So yeah, just setting up an entity that's legal that you can pay taxes on. Paying taxes on
crypto is pretty insane in a country that has no kind of guidance. So just getting to where we've
gotten stuff nobody sees is like a miracle, to be honest. The fact that we have, we got a regulatory
classification, then we needed a tax classification, which was different. So all that stuff was
crazy amount of work and stress. And that is done, which is nice. But it was a huge undertaking.
Yeah, now the fun part. With stablecoins today, you can hold dollars and send dollars all across
the world. That's amazing. Call that a phase one. You guys have built the system you were just talking
about. Call that a phase two where hopefully you can hold and send U.S. dollars. You can also hold
and send other assets, other treasuries and trade them against each other very easily without this
reliance on an institutional account structure, without market hour constraints, all these legacy
systems or legacy limitations. Is this crypto's killer use case in your view? Is that what we've
been building for maybe at risk of upsetting the Bitcoin folks?
I think so. I mean, the Bitcoin folks, they have their use case, which is an awesome product that
stores value and it's independent from an economy. But I think crypto has a few other
awesome use cases. But I think one is just connecting the world efficiently through DeFi.
There's this awesome book called Mystery to Capital, which you should read, you may have read.
Just creating a universal process for trading across the world is an insane feat.
What I view as crypto's biggest use case is what the world's biggest market is today,
which is the forex market. If I can remove an efficiency, like probably the most efficient
channel in the world of sending money is the U.S. to Mexico. Our product has increased the yield that
you could get by 3% and removed the cost of on and off ramping to near zero. That's the most
efficient channel. So now when I start to hit like Nigeria and Bangladesh, it's going to be
way more efficient in the future. So I think the biggest opportunity is bringing the security of
DeFi or bringing forex onto DeFi and enabling the trust and security of DeFi to facilitate
exchange across the globe. The blockchain world has done really well building the function
f of x, but no one's really done well building x, which is the input. We're focused on the things
people will trade in the x. We've looked at the world and we've said that stable bond we feel
solves three problems store value and investment and payments. So if we look at those characteristics
across the nations, what are the top 15? So our goal for the next two years is to onboard those
top 15 countries that have the highest store value, the highest yields, and are most used for
remittances. We think if we can get those 15 assets on chain, we've brought 90% of the forex
market on chain and we've made it more efficient, better investment, quicker, more reliable. So I
think that is crypto's killer use case. The second is on and off ramping nations. So to me,
connecting a nation to crypto or the blockchain is like connecting a nation to the internet
or connecting the nation to electricity. So in many cases, we want to be the first person
in these remote areas to provide an interest bearing asset denominated that currency that can
on and off ramp for near free. And then we felt we've unwrapped that country. Those are like the
two kind of scenarios that we really think about. And in those cases, as you guys see continued
adoption, do you think people will look at these stable coins and stable bonds each day? Will it be
I pull up my phone and my app and I see my balance. I know they're stable coins or will this be hidden
behind some, whether it's an agentic system, whether it's a messaging interface, a super app,
something like that. I think in a perfect world for us, people don't even really know they're
using etherfuse. They look at a wallet, like I'm trying to think of somebody you guys know,
like El Dorado. And they think El Dorado has an mxn account. It's not etherfuse state days or
etherfuse mxne. It's just abstracted, right? I think that's the killer use case. I think that's
when people nobody cares, like the real world doesn't care what it is, you know, or if it was
AWS or Azure or GCP, you know, they just want the app to work. So for us, we're trying to not be
the last thing you see. We're trying to be like that AWS for sovereign debt. So I think in the
future, people won't really know it runs on the blockchain or what it is. It's just a wallet.
It's amazing. I've found that the people I know who actually know where stable coins are being used,
especially ones who use crypto, are the ones I know who are from the most vulnerable or
difficult markets from a geopolitical and economic perspective. I have family in Iran because my dad
grew up in Iran and I was talking about crypto in my family and my Iranian grand uncle knew exactly
about stable coins and how they move and all that because there's just such a distrust of how money
works. Whereas PYUSD and even people I know who might be in the Western Hemisphere and hold dollars
through a crypto account, they've no idea it's sitting in stable coins. It is interesting. I think
part of that leads to how we got here too. If you grew up or you're familiar with an area where
the currency fluctuates, you're yearning for a safe stable asset. In your opinion, that's the dollar.
If you go to Argentina like you're saying or Iran, they know what it is. They can finally get
access through stable coins. Sometimes I wonder, why are we the only people focusing on non-US assets?
And I think it's because we brought the alternative perspective too. So just to play off that, I think
it's interesting. We have access to US dollars here in the US, but I don't have access to emerging
market investments quite efficiently as I think I should. So it's kind of interesting how where you
grew up in the context of your life leads to how you view opportunity too.
It's such a world-centric view, especially in the context of history. I was having a conversation
the other day where we were talking about how no one knew the Roman Empire fell until hundreds of
years later. To take a view that you only ever want to own US dollars is to say that you think
the US will be the only dominant currency for the foreseeable future of history ever.
Which maybe not. Hopefully, yeah, hopefully for us.
I win-win no matter what, but I don't think so, especially if you look at what Europe is doing
with mica. It was fundamentally built to protect their sovereignty and their currency. If you look
they have restrictions on non-European limits and things like that, that they don't have if your
currency is mica compliance and denominator in the euro. I think we're going to see this start to
happen more and more across the world where you have these regulatory bodies say almost like these
new tariffs. I look at mica as a tariff, to be honest. It's like some added complexity to promote
an internal economy. And I think we'll start to see those with stablecoins probably in the next
five years or so. Hopefully, we're well-established and we can meet those demands. But yeah, I think
we're going to see the world change quite a bit in the next five years.
You guys are in a very interesting position because you are going to be offering these assets to what
is a really wide demographic of people when you think about the different profiles in these countries.
From my perspective, it seems like it's a bit of a jump ball in terms of the offerings of these
assets and controlling the end user in the sense that it could be JP Morgan, it could be Apple,
your former employer, it could be a government, it could even be NATO or some kind of multinational
organization. Maybe that's a bit of a stretch. But I think you understand the sentiment. Do you
think they will all try and get into this game? In my view, it's only logical that they would.
But I'm curious who you think moves here and then who is the issuer who's controlling the end user
and the future? Ironically, I think the only thing that has enabled the legacy financial system
to not completely dominate the blockchain ecosystem is fear and regulation because they have a lot
to lose. So regulation saved us. Regulation has saved us. This gray area has enabled the
opportunity for us to have upward mobility. I mean, just think about it. Like, Tether is
about $130 billion. Yeah. No, what's that line? Regulation favors the incumbent, right?
Yeah. JP Morgan Chase is $4 trillion. JP Morgan Chase doesn't need Tether and they don't need
Circle at all. The second they know how they can operate and it's clear, they're all issuing
stablecoins and no one's going to care. I have Chase. If my account is underlying stablecoins,
JP Morgan Coin, I won't care. I don't think about it. I trust them enough.
I think it's going to be interesting to see what happens in the US. I do believe that the
established players like Tether and Circle will survive and they'll have a place. But I think
these new ones who are, and I hate to say this because I like a lot of these people and I hope
I'm wrong, but I think it'll be a less trusted resource once regulation is clear. Unless you
get in the billions of volume or you have some niche, pretty sure that the banks are going to come
for us all. Now, our benefit is these emerging markets are way behind in a lot of stuff.
When we issue an asset, we're like the first company that comes in to do it. I think we have
10 to 15 years to make an impact before those regulatory bodies really do enough work to
let their banking systems issue stablecoins. That's our philosophy. 10 to 15 years isn't bad.
Not too bad. We can do a lot with that. But especially just looking at Mexico, it's so
old. How it works is so bureaucratic compared to the US, which is also slow. I think before banks,
and we're talking to a lot of them by the way, so we understand their dilemma, before Mexican banks
feel comfortable enough to issue large volumes, a lot has to happen. I think the US has to move
first. It was really strange how we heard no's. Some of our assets are in Europe. In the early
stages, the problem was finding a custodian who would say yes to us, and we got turned down by a
lot of people. Interesting. That was an operation chokepoint 2.0 issue in Europe, just like we
have here. It's crazy. These are big banks too. I don't want to name names, but the second Trump
won, I had three of them email me back saying, hey, we're looking to be more competitive.
I was like, dude, it was really hard to find our initial custodians. All our custodians are large,
well trusted. That was part of the problem. I think the US leads and the rest of the world
follows their guidance. If you take those banks or any others as an example, were they building
crypto product? Were they trying to get ready when Trump wasn't president and we were in a hostile
regime? Or do you think they're a little flat-footed? I think they're flat-footed. I think
the only emerging, it's not an emerging market, but the only bank that I'd say global that addresses
emerging market needs that's really trying, was trying back then, was BBVA. They have a platform
in Switzerland. They've been working on something, so they were kind of trying, but the sense of
urgency that they should have had was definitely not there. This is a huge disruptor, especially
for emerging markets. 50% of BBVA's revenue comes just from Mexico as an example. In my opinion,
I would be doing everything I can if I was the CEO of BBVA to ensure that I'm leading this space in
Mexico. We work with them. They work with us. They're friendly to us, so maybe we can help them
get there. I think that they are now flat-footed and trying to recover quite a bit.
In the US, we've made major strides. People get very down on some of these topics, but the Bitcoin
ETF exchange trading on traditional brokerages, in terms of just giving normal people access to
crypto, my sense is that that's happened a lot less elsewhere. It's funny, in our local circumstance,
I think that that is probably actually a stymied DeFi adoption to a sense. In my view,
it's people used to go to DeFi because traditional trading opportunities were limited,
and now Coinbase is listing more assets. You can go and buy the Bitcoin ETF on various brokerages.
Do you think more globally that that lack of crypto trading experience with traditional
banks' asset managers pushes people to DeFi? Is that a growth catalyst for DeFi?
Yeah, when regulation is unclear, it's the only launchpad. There is CeFi, but is there a central
light? I don't know the best way to say CeFi, but... CeFi works. Okay, CeFi. CeFi, in my experience,
has felt a lot like extortion, where it's like, hey, we're the only way for you to bridge to the
blockchain, so give us a bunch of money and we'll let your token. DeFi has been a way that we could
use skills to grow without any gatekeepers. My opinion over the next 10 years, centralized
exchanges' influence will be reduced, especially as things become more clear in ways that a wallet
could directly bridge you to the blockchain, not necessarily a big company. I think DeFi's influence
will increase for a few reasons. Even though regulation clearing up will make it easier
for you to get access, there's still going to be this nuance. So if you take equities as an example,
we deliberately chose not to engage in equities because once you start selling in equity,
there's 100x more issues you have to worry about. In my opinion, all these new equity platforms
coming out, they'll have these restrictions, which will make it harder for you to trade,
off-ramping, on-ramping, and things like that. So I think DeFi will still have a place where someone
who has a regulatory body that is favorable to them that can issue on DeFi will have an asset
that is more freely transferable. Both things are going to happen. There'll be better traditional
access using blockchain technology available to people in highly regulated areas, but also
there will be certain things that can only be done at DeFi like non-restricted tokens that can
be freely transferable that someone in Venezuela could buy on DeFi or that'll have to happen on
DeFi and there will always be a market for that. And I want to pick your brain on your views for
the future a little bit. And first in that vein, you mentioned wallets. For an ether fuse, for example,
is better wallets one of the best things that can happen for your guy's business,
looking at how you're acquiring users? Best case scenario is you're a big wallet, you get my SDK
and you mint and burn directly. Better wallets is our favorite partners, right? There's nothing
in between the user and us except for this interface and there's a lot for the wallet to gain
and there's a lot for the user to have. So hypothetically... So if you're a wallet listening...
Yeah, if you're a wallet, come talk to me. I can enable you multi-currency accounts
that are yield bearing that earn you different revenue while you just fundamentally give your
users a wise experience. Wise as bank accounts in different currencies, they don't earn yield
and they let you send money. I can do that same thing for you just by giving you my SDK if you're
a self-custody wallet. It's the best business in the book, isn't it? You just hold assets for
someone and earn money for doing it for something that you don't even control or issue? Yeah,
and even if you're a self-custody wallet, you're not technically even holding them. It's just
you work through our affiliate program and you earn a portion of the yield that that customer
generates. So you don't even need an MTL license. That's exactly like Coinbase's circle agreement,
right? There's no difference there, really? Yeah, exactly. And Coinbase wallet does this.
Coinbase, I don't know what your thoughts are. I think they're going to do really well. The way
they're vertically integrated, they already show preference over currencies. And so if you buy
MXNE, it would be like a preferred asset. They really get it and they're able to do it because
they have the whole stack. I've heard they're going to become a bank here, which is a killer use case
too. So it seems like they get it. They're making a push into non-USD stablecoins,
as I'm sure you've seen. Yeah, we're a big part of it. If you see their dashboards,
MXNE is on it. Well, in that vein, and to close out a bit here, where do you see their fuses or
where do you hope their fuses in coming months and years? And what's the worldview that pushes
you guys forward in the right direction? Our aim for the next two years is to onboard 90% of all
assets used for remittances, the last mile, and that we can on and off ramp onto those assets.
You can mint and burn, essentially, from the local banking system. So that's the next two years.
The next five years, every country, we have an interest-bearing asset denominated in that currency
that can on and off ramp, and we facilitate local stablecoins to nominate those currencies.
So that's the goal for us is to on-ramp those countries and bring forex on chain. And we want
to be laser focused on building the most robust assets with transparency, with third-party checks
and validation and verifications, improving our liquidity-freezed asset, and the utility of on
and off ramping those assets. So next five years, we hope to bring forex on chain through our assets
on any platform, on any blockchain, and that that is a trusted resource that either fuses a
trusted brand just like Circle is or Tether is. Awesome. Well, we'll leave it there with the hopes
of a more globally economically interconnected world. Dave, thanks for joining us, and hopefully
you'll come back soon. All right. Thanks, Wyatt. Appreciate it. Thanks for listening to another
episode of On the Brink with Castle Island. To find out more about Castle Island, visit
castleisland.vc. To listen to all of our podcast episodes, please go to onthebrink-podcast.com
or just click on the tab in our website. Thanks for listening.